Henry Tao

Email https://github.com/once-ler
Twitter https://twitter.com/htaox
LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/henry-tao-1639a54/

Objective:

Obtain a position with an innovative IT team that will enable me to use my strong systems integration skills and apply design principles such as event sourcing and domain driven design to build predictable real-time systems and applications.

Summary:

I am a determined and highly-motivated developer and database expert with eighteen years experience ranging from startups to large enterprise organizations. I am a relentless learner who craves to build elegant highly performant backend systems as well as beautiful user-focused client applications.

Expertise and Key Skills:

Actively Using

C++(11, 14); ECMAScript(6, 7); C#(3, 6); React(15); Node.js(5, 6, 7); PostgreSQL(9.6); MongoDB(3.2); SQL Server(2008); WCF(3.5); Docker(1.13)

Used in Past

D3.js(3.5)^{2+ (2013)}; Angular.js(1.3)^{2+ (2015)}; Oracle(10G)^{1+ (2009)}; Backbone.js^{2+ (2014)}; Python^{1- (2014)}; C^{1 (2011)}; Reporting Services^{3-4 (2010)}; WPF^{1 (2011)}; Silverlight^{2 (2011)}; Windows Forms^{2 (2008)}

Professional Experience:

NYU Langone Health, New York, NY

Lead Developer, Research IT 2013 - Present

- Designed and deployed MongoDB sharded cluster with 15 database instances (5 replica sets with 3 instances each), 5 config servers, and 5 mongos across 5 servers.
 - Allows the consumption and processing of HL7 (ADT_A08 & ADT_A31) messages; 30K per day/2.5MM per month.
 - Easily retain TB's of storage.
- Designed and implemented the Research Integration Layer that propagates real-time updates across multiple application domains including:
 - Epic EHR (Electronic Health Record)
 - Study creation in Epic from CRMS
 - Patient enrollment in Epic from CRMS
 - Synchronization of patient demographics between Epic and CRMS
 - PeopleSoft Finance
 - Proposal and award creation in PeopleSoft from Grants
 - Payment creation in CRMS from PeopleSoft
 - o IRB (Internal Review Board)
 - CRMS (Clinical Research Managment System)
 - IACUC (Institutional Animal Care and Use Committee)

Fluitec Wind, Jersey City, NJ

Front-end Lead Developer 2012 - 2013

Developed custom interative data visualizations for post-process Hadoop resultsets of wind turbines

UNFCU, Long Island City, NY

Consultant 2009 - 2012

- Developed and implemented mission critical ETL that powers the enterprise data-warehouse
 - Replaced incumbent solution that took 17+ hours daily to complete and reduced it to 45 minutes

Ellen Tracy, New York, NY

Systems Integration Specialist 2008 - 2009

Integrated 2 major retailers to enterprise Oracle ERP

UNFCU, Long Island City, NY

DBA and DWH Report Writer 2006 - 2008

John Wiley & Sons, Hoboken, NJ

Senior Systems Analyst and Programmer - HRIS 1999 - 2005

National Financial Services, New York, NY

Mutual Fund Representative 1997 - 1999

JET Programme, Awaji Island, Japan

Assistant English Teacher 1995 - 1997

Education:

SUNY at Buffalo, 1990 - 1994

Bachelor of Science (BS), Finance and MIS, Summa Cum Laude

Projects:

LongBall-FHIR, 2017 - Present

• FHIR Modeling in C++14

Store, 2016 - Present

• Shared API for implementing event sourcing and event store for C++ and C#

Rx-Web, 2016 - Present

- Web server implementing observable semantics. Comes in 2 flavors:
 - o C++11
 - o ECMAScript 7

Vinyl, 2017 - Present

· Yet another React primitive components library

React FHIR, 2016

• FHIR Application built with React/Redux

DocGraph, 2014

 Process 132 Million edges from Medicare using Hadoop and HBase inside a cluster of Docker containers